P.O. Box 233 Maine, NY 13802 (575) 224-0080

# Robert Ross Peterson

http://robertpeterson.io contact@robertpeterson.io

#### SUMMARY

Twelve years of IT experience that includes consulting, development, architecture, and management. Hands-on professional who leads by example. Enjoys new technology and building elegant systems with best practices. Currently specialize in iOS / Android freelance projects.

## **EDUCATION**

M.S. Computer Science, University of Florida B.S. Computer Engineering with High Honors, University of Florida Gainesville, FL

### **EXPERIENCE**

Present

#### **MOBILE DEVELOPER** – robertpeterson.io

Massachusetts

- Freelance and consulting practice specializing in iOS, Android, and web development
- Portfolio encompasses academic, non-profit, and gaming sectors
- Native, Hybrid-Ionic, Hybrid-Webview, Java, Objective-C, Swift, C++, HTML, CSS3, ES6

2012 - 2015

## HEALTHCARE IT MANAGER - Texas Health & Human Services (HHSC)

Austin, TX

- Managed backend systems for Medicaid, SNAP Food Benefits, Prenatal Healthcare, and Affordable Care Act (ACA)
- Systems process benefits for 15% of Texas population or ~4.4 million
- Served as team leader for 8 staff members and various auxiliary consultants
- Through strategic hiring of talent, automation projects, and restructuring of team processes, transformed team from below average to most productive in department
- Designed security implementation for Texas/Federal ACA system using DES cryptography, LDAP, and DataPower XSLT

√parseix

CO-FOUNDER - parseix.com

Williamsville, NY

 Designed and implemented front-end of initial offering using HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, & Highcharts

Successfully hired and created requirements documentation for visual designer

2010 - 2012

2010 - 2012

INTEGRATION ARCHITECT — IBM Tivoli

Austin, TX

Agile project lead responsible for ten engineers for Business Service Management offering

Contributions enabled successful launch of IBM product in 1Q 2012

2005 - 2010

IT CONSULTANT – IBM Websphere

Austin, TX

- Conducted business internationally for over 50 customers, many of which are Fortune 500 companies, in industries including financial, insurance, aerospace, energy, and retail
- Developed complex client solutions with a variety of technology including jQuery/Dojo JavaScript, CSS, REST, JavaEE, SQL, XSLT, and Web Services

2003 BOEING IT ANALYST - Boeing Integrated Defense Systems

St Louis, MO

Designed Oracle PL/SQL database application for F-16, F-18, C-17, & missile production

## **NOTABLE PUBLICATIONS**



- Book: Persistence In the Enterprise, IBM Press, May 2008 (ISBN-0131587560)
- Book: WebSphere Application Server V6, IBM Redbooks, May 2005 (ISBN-0738490601)
- Bridging Web 2.0 and SOA with DataPower, WebSphere Technical Journal, September 2011
- Integrating WebSphere Service Registry with Tivoli, IBM developerWorks, December 2010
- Leverage Existing WAS J2EE Resources with Apache Geronimo, SYS-CON, May 2006
- US Patent 20090019421: Runtime Machine Supported Method Level Caching, January 2009
- US Patent 20080133538: Background File Sharing in Peer-To-Peer (P2P) File Sharing Network, June 2008

## NOTABLE CONFERENCE TALKS

Pulse2012



- Tivoli and WebSphere Integration, IBM PULSE Conference, March 2012
- DataPower in a Web 2.0 World, IBM IMPACT Conference, May 2010
- Case Studies for WebSphere Service Registry, WebSphere Services Technical Conference, April 2008
- Aspect-Oriented Programming with Eclipse for J2EE, WebSphere Technical Conference, March 2006

# **ADDITIONAL DISTINCTIONS**

- Texas HHSC Leadership Community Member, invited to leadership meetings and training
- IBM Master Inventor, title awarded for outstanding IP contributions to IBM
- IBM General Manager Award (among numerous others OTAA, Stock Awards, Bravo Awards)